Guide to the Hisham Khatib Collection of photographic prints AD.MC.030
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Prints from Africa and Asia/various ephemera, ref717; Dominic Winter Books (2008) (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
  - Football Match in Lagos., 1922; ref264; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Men; Women; Nigeria; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Outdoors; Group Portraits; Hats; Facial Hair; Boys; Children; Football; Sports; Smoking
  - Man working under a thatched tent in camp at Chantak Siam, 1903; ref265; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Men; Tents; Household Appliances; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Outdoors; Thailand; Houses
  - "Siluro Tours" on Table Mountain., Circa 1880 - 1920; ref266; Ravenscroft, Thomas Daniel, 1851 - 1948; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Mountains/Hills; Landscapes; Women; Boys; South Africa; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Outdoors; Children; Group Portraits
  - "Colonial and Indian Exhibition: the Dominion of Canada" from the Illustrated London News, 1886; ref269; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Art; Canada; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; Canada; English Writing; Men; Women; Religious Holiday; Printed Materials
  - Clipping "The Sioux War- A Trio of Indian Chiefs" from The Graphic., 30 December 1876; ref273; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Regional/National Dress; Men; Women; Art; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; United States of America; Printed Materials
  - Page from "China's Millions" with a sketch of The Custom House, Shanghai, Circa 1877; ref274; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Art; Shanghai, China; Boats/Ships; Crowds; Buildings; Regional/National Dress; Books; Newspaper Clippings; Newspapers/Magazines; English Writing; Architecture; Trade
  - Engraving of "Native Tea Gardens", Shanghai from the Illustrated London News, 29 August 1863; ref275; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Art; Crowds; Regional/National Dress; Shanghai, China; Newspapers/Magazines; Newspaper Clippings; English Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Printed Materials
  - Illustration of "Group of Disciplined Chinese Soldiers with European Officer" from the Illustrated London News., 29 August 1863; ref276; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Art; Group Portraits; Military/Soldiers; Weapons; Guns; China; Regional/National Dress; Uniforms; Newspapers/Magazines; Newspaper Clippings; English Writing; Men; Turbans
- Lehnert and Landrock, Tunis, ref718 (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
  - A desert scene with a group of people sitting around a fire with a camel (no. 840), Circa 1910s; ref279; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Camels; Deserts; Children; Bedouins; Tunis, Tunisia; Regional/National Dress; Boys; Girls; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Animals; Women; Turbans
  - Three men and a child by an oasis (no. 917)., Circa 1910s; ref280; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Palm Trees; Buildings; Men; Boys; Bedouins; Regional/National Dress; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Tunis, Tunisia; Children; Group Portraits; Landscapes
  - A portrait of a Morrocan Arab holding a rifle gun (no. 102), Circa 1910s; ref281; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Individual Portraits; Guns; Weapons; Bags/Purses; Regional/National Dress; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Tunis, Tunisia; Men; Facial Hair; Turbans
  - A portrait of two women with veiled faces and white clothing standing at an entrance (no. 201), Circa 1910s; ref282; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Arabic Writing; Women; Regional/National Dress; Head Covers/Veils; Jewelry; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Buildings; Tunis, Tunisia; Outdoors
  - A desert scene of a group of people and a camel resting around a fire (no. 841)., Circa 1910s; ref283; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Camels; Bedouins; Deserts; Tunis, Tunisia; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Animals; Boys; Girls; Children; Women
  - A portrait of a young boy with a basket (no. 123), Circa 1910s; ref284; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Boys; Individual Portraits; Bags/Purses; Tunis, Tunisia; Gelatin Silver Prints; Photographic Prints; Children
  - A man playing the flute with a flock of sheep (no. 901), Circa 1910s; ref285; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: ref194-ref229)
    Sheep; Bedouins; Musical Instruments; Palm Trees; Tunis, Tunisia; Men; Animals; Photographic Prints; Gelatin Silver Prints; Outdoors; Individual Portraits
- A Journey to Palestine, Egypt and Athens, ref719 (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
  - A view of a street in Jerusalem, Circa 1880 - 1910; ref287; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Jerusalem; Streets/Roads; Buildings; Men; Children; Boys; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Outdoors
  - A view of Ramla, between Jaffa and Jerusalem, Circa 1880 - 1910; ref288; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Jerusalem; Ramla/ar-Ramlah; Jaffa; Landscapes; Streets/Roads; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Palestine; Cemeteries
  - No.247 Portes du St.Sépulcre (Gates of the Church of the Holy Sepulchre)., Circa 1880; ref289; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Religious Sites; Architecture; Men; Priests/Clergymen; Street Vendors; Jerusalem; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Churches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Facial Hair; Group Portraits; Palestine
  - Maison de Simon le tanneur à Jaffa (A view of the House of Simon the Tanner in Jaffa), Circa 1880 - 1910; ref290; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    French Writing; Buildings; Tel Aviv/Tall ʾabīb; Jaffa; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Houses; Group Portraits; Head Covers/Veils; Pottery; Facial Hair; Religious Sites
  - A road between Jerusalem and Bethlehem., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref291; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Streets/Roads; Horses; Men; Buildings; Landscapes; Jerusalem; Bethlehem; Palestine; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Animals; Mountains/Hills
  - Two women walking towards the Zion Gate in Jerusalem., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref292; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Jerusalem; Architecture; Women; Men; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Palestine; Buildings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - Two women holding Jaffa lemons on a vessel., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref293; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Women; Group Portraits; Boats/Ships; Seas; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Palestine; Hats; Palestine; Food
  - A view of Mount Moriah Temple area (Temple Mount)., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref294; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Jerusalem; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Men; Women; Children; Photographic Prints; Palestine; Religious Sites; Buildings; Albumen Prints; Group Portraits; Architecture; Churches; Mosques; Regional/National Dress
  - A view outside Temple Area at Mount Moriah (Temple Mount)., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref295; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Jerusalem; Religious Sites; Architecture; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf; Palestine; Landscapes; Buildings; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes
  - A view of a street in Jerusalem, Circa 1880 - 1910; ref296; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Streets/Roads; Jerusalem; Palestine; Buildings; Children; Men; Women; Street Vendors; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Architecture
  - A group entering the Pool of Siloam., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref297; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Siloam/Silwan; Religious Sites; Women; Men; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Jerusalem; Palestine; Group Portraits; Hats; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A boy wearing a keffiyeh., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref298; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Boys; Individual Portraits; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Palestine; Outdoors; Children
  - Chapel of the Virgin (Chapel of the Milk Grotto) in Bethlehem, Circa 1880 - 1910; ref299; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Bethlehem; Palestine; Religious Sites; Architecture; Churches; Buildings; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Paintings; Chapel of the Milk Grotto of Our Lady
  - A view of St. George's Cathedral and bishop's house in Jerusalem., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref300; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Jerusalem; Churches; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Palestine; Religious Crosses
  - A view of town of Bethany, or Al-Eizariya, Circa 1880 - 1910; ref301; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Al-Eizariya/Bethany; Buildings; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Landscapes; Palestine; Architecture
  - A group walking towards a cemetery outside the Walls of Jerusalem., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref302; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Jerusalem; Architecture; Women; Outdoors; Dome of the Rock/Qubbat al-Sakhrah; Streets/Roads; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Men; Buildings; Palestine; Cemeteries; Umbrellas/Parasols; English Writing; Temple Mount/al-Ḥaram al-Šarīf
  - Doors of the Church of Holy Sepulchre and a Turkish guard., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref303; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Religious Sites; Architecture; Churches; Church of the Holy Sepulchre; Men; Women; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Jerusalem; Individual Portraits; Regional/National Dress; Palestine; Buildings; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Hats
  - Several boats preparing to depart by the Nile, Egypt / Portal of the Temple of Khonsu in Karnak, Egypt, Circa 1880 - 1910; ref304; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Nile River; Rivers; Boats/Ships; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Palm Trees; Temples; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Religious Sites; Egypt
  - The Pyramid of Khafre and the Great Sphinx of Giza., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref305; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    The Great Sphinx of Giza; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Landscapes; Deserts; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A group of European travellers on camels, in front of the Great Sphinx of Giza., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref306; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Pyramids; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Giza, Egypt; Group Portraits; Women; Men; Camels; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Animals; Regional/National Dress; Facial Hair; Fez/Tarboush; Hats; Turbans
  - A view of Medinet Habu., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref307; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Palaces; Buildings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Egypt; Temples; Religious Sites
  - Courtyard of Mosque of Muhammad Ali., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref308; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Men; Women; Mosques; Cairo, Egypt; Buildings; Religious Sites; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints
  - A group of European travellers on camels, in front of the Great Sphinx of Giza, Egypt, Circa 1880 - 1910; ref309; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Pyramids; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Giza, Egypt; Women; Men; Group Portraits; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Camels; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Animals; Turbans; Facial Hair; Regional/National Dress; Fez/Tarboush; Hats
  - Roda Island., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref310; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Nile River; Boats/Ships; Children; Men; Women; Buildings; Palm Trees; Rivers; Landscapes; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Architecture; Cairo, Egypt; Transportation
  - The Al-Masalla obelisk in Heliopolis, Egypt., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref311; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Heliopolis, Cairo, Egypt; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Albumen Prints; Photographic Prints; Buildings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A view of the Tower of the Winds in Athens, Greece, Circa 1880 - 1910; ref312; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Athens, Greece; Architecture; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Outdoors
  - A funeral in a cemetery of a Greek church in Athens., Circa 1880 - 1910; ref313; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref256-ref278)
    Athens, Greece; Priests/Clergymen; Men; Women; Churches; Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Funeral Proceedings; Buildings; Cemeteries; Religious Sites
- Babylonian Expedition, University of Pennsylvania, Circa 1888-1920; ref720 (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
  - Men in canoes on the marshes and canals near Babylon., Circa 1888-1900; ref315; Haynes, John Henry; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Boats/Ships; Men; Regional/National Dress; Rivers; Landscapes; Transportation; English Writing
  - A group portrait of men gathered besides some ruins., Circa 1910-1920; ref316; Underwood & Underwood, 242 West 55th Street, New York (USA).; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Men; Animals; Horses; Guns; Regional/National Dress; Landscapes; Mountains/Hills; Weapons; English Writing
  - Buffaloes in the Hawizeh Marshes., Circa 1888-1900; ref317; Haynes, John Henry; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Animals; Landscapes; Rivers; Cattle/Cows; English Writing
  - Camels grazing near Nuffar (Afak)., Circa 1888-1900; ref318; Haynes, John Henry; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Animals; Camels; Landscapes; Men; Regional/National Dress; English Writing
  - A boat in a canal in Iraq., Circa 1888-1900; ref319; Haynes, John Henry; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Landscapes; Rivers; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Men; Regional/National Dress; English Writing
  - Ziggurat and Parthian fortress, Nuffar (Afak)., Circa 1888-1900; ref320; Haynes, John Henry; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Forts/Castles; English Writing
  - Ziggurat and Parthian fortress, Nuffar (Afak)., Circa 1888-1900; ref321; Haynes, John Henry; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Buildings; Architecture; Children; Boys; Regional/National Dress; Forts/Castles; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; English Writing
  - Men and children by the banks of a river in Iraq., Circa 1910-1920; ref322; Keystone-Underwood, Keystone View Co. 219 East 44th Street, New York (USA).; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Men; Children; Boys; Animals; Goats; Landscapes; Rivers; Regional/National Dress; English Writing
  - Two boys sitting on a hill overlooking the Euphrates river., Circa 1910-1920; ref323; Keystone-Underwood, Keystone View Co. 219 East 44th Street, New York (USA).; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Euphrates River; Children; Boys; Outdoors; Landscapes; Rivers; Palm Trees; Regional/National Dress; Hats; Buildings; Architecture; Agriculture/Farms; English Writing; Mountains/Hills
  - Archaeological site within the ancient city of Babylon, cuneiform tablet in the foreground., Circa 1910-1920; ref324; Keystone-Underwood, Keystone View Co. 219 East 44th Street, New York (USA).; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Men; Regional/National Dress; Landscapes; Turbans; English Writing
  - The processional street in the ancient city of Babylon., Circa 1910-1920; ref325; Keystone-Underwood, Keystone View Co. 219 East 44th Street, New York (USA).; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Buildings; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Men; Regional/National Dress; Architecture; English Writing
  - A man standing against walls flanking the processional street in the ancient city of Babylon., Circa 1910-1920; ref326; Underwood & Underwood, 242 West 55th Street, New York (USA).; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Iraq; Men; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Regional/National Dress; Individual Portraits; English Writing; Outdoors
  - Two men writing, a third leans against the wall., Circa 1910-1920; ref327; Underwood & Underwood, 242 West 55th Street, New York (USA).; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only: 030_ref315-ref327)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Men; Regional/National Dress; Buildings; Hats; Turbans; Fez/Tarboush; Pens/Inkwells; Carpets/Rugs; Facial Hair; English Writing; Iraq; Workers; Group Portraits; Books; Streets/Roads
- Egypt and Yemen, Circa 1867-1900; ref721 (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
  - 1094 Le Caire, Mosquée de Sultan Kalaoun extérieur (A view of Qalawun complex in Cairo)., Circa 1867-1880; ref328; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Sites; Mosques; Animals; Transportation; Streets/Roads; Carriages/Coaches; French Writing
  - 142 Karnak Avenue centrale de la salle hypostyle, Égypte (A view of Karnak Central Avenue of the Hypostyle Hall, Egypt)., Circa 1867-1880; ref329; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Luxor, Egypt; French Writing; Individual Portraits; Outdoors; Buildings; Architecture; Palm Trees; Temples; Religious Sites; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Regional/National Dress; Men; Egyptian Hieroglyphics; Turbans
  - Men on camels with the pyramids of Giza in the background., Circa 1867-1880; ref330; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Giza, Egypt; French Writing; Pyramids; Monuments/Memorials; Palm Trees; Buildings; Nile River; Men; Camels; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Animals
  - Caire, pris du Mokattam (A view of Cairo taken from Mokattam)., Circa 1867-1880; ref331; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Buildings; Religious Sites; Forts/Castles; Mokattam, Cairo, Egypt; Mosques
  - No.160 Pillars with statues at a facade of a temple., Circa 1867-1880; ref332; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Egypt; Temples; Religious Sites; Statues/Sculptures; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Egyptian Hieroglyphics
  - Village et pyramides pendant l'inondation (A view of a village and pyramids during the flood)., Circa 1867-1880; ref333; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Pyramids; Cairo, Egypt; Group Portraits; Camels; Regional/National Dress; Animals; Nile River; Rivers; Buildings; Palm Trees; French Writing; Monuments/Memorials; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Men; Children; Boys; Giza, Egypt
  - Le Cairo, Le nilométre de l'île de Roda (A view of nilometer at the island of Roda, Cairo)., Circa 1867-1880; ref334; Bonfils, Felix; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Buildings; Palm Trees; French Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Rivers; Nile River; Landscapes
  - Intérieur de la Mosquée Amrou (A view of the interior of the Mosque of Amr)., Circa 1856-1889; ref335; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Religious Sites; Architecture; Mosques; Buildings; French Writing
  - Mihrab de la Mosquée Saida Nafissa No.550 (A mihrab of Al Sayeda Nafisa Mosque)., Circa 1856-1889; ref336; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Religious Sites; Mosques; Arabic Calligraphy
  - Kavan de Baraca No.553 (A wooden inlaid hexagonal dish)., Circa 1856-1889; ref337; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; French Writing; Art
  - Fauteuil provenant de la Mosquée Kismass Il Is Haky (A chair from Amir Qijmas al-Ishaqi / Abu Heriba mosque)., Circa 1856-1889; ref338; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Religious Sites; Mosques; French Writing; Art; Cairo, Egypt
  - Porte de la Mosquée de Imam Chaffy No.542 (A door from the Imam Shafi'i Mosque)., Circa 1856-1889; ref339; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Art; Religious Sites; Mosques; Architecture; French Writing
  - Intérieur de la Mosquée Bourban No.44 (A view of the interior of Al-Burdayni Mosque, Cairo)., Circa 1856-1889; ref340; Abdullah Frères, Constantinople (Beyoglu, Istanbul, Turkey); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Cairo, Egypt; Religious Sites; Architecture; Mosques; Buildings; French Writing; English Writing
  - No.134 Saqqarah, Statue de Sesostris renversée (The statue of Ramesses II in Saqqara, Egypt)., Circa 1887; ref341; Béchard, Émile, Circa 1860-1880; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only - 030_ref328-ref350)
    Photographic Prints; Albumen Prints; Saqqara, Egypt; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Statues/Sculptures; Men; Regional/National Dress; Palm Trees; Outdoors; Turbans